# Gabriel Doon

Virginia Beach, VA | 757-390-1716 | doongs@dukes.jmu.edu | http://w3stu.cs.jmu.edu/doongs/

## **Objective**

I am an undergraduate student seeking to acquire workplace and research experience where I can apply my three years of
computer-science education and team-oriented work skills to professional tasks; additionally, I am looking to utilize my years of
music experience within both performance, education, and computer science research.

# **Education**

### INTERNATIONAL BACCALURIATE DIPLOMA | CLASS OF 2019 | PRINCESS ANNE HIGH SCHOOL

- Graduate with honors from the Geneva, Switzerland based International Baccalaureate Program
- Bilingual certification in French

#### BACHELOR OF SCIENCE | CLASS OF 2023 | JAMES MADISON UNIVERSITY - HONORS COLLEGE

- Major: Computer Science
- Minors: Mathematics, Jazz Studies, Honors Interdisciplinary Studies
- STEM Second Century Scholarship Recipient James Madison University
- Classes taken in Calculus, Statistics, Discrete Math, Java Programming, Software Engineering, Jazz Improvisation

# **Skills & Abilities**

## LEADERSHIP AND TEAMWORK

- IMU CS Ambassadors Outreach Leader
- Marching Royal Dukes and JMU Jazz Chamber Ensemble member
- Workshop leader for JMU Expand Your Horizons 2020 event

#### **TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE**

- Java: sorting, searching, abstract data structures, I/O, class design, swing GUI
- Proficient in Scrum process framework and Git version control through GitHub

## **Experience**

#### **VOLUNTEER | TIDEWATER COMMUNITY COLLEGE | APRIL 2019 - AUGUST 2019**

Involved in the refurbishing, upgrade, repair, and technical support for the Computers for Student Success program

## PROFESSIONAL MUSICIAN ON TENOR SAXOPHONE AND PIANO | TIDEWATER WINDS | CURRENT

· Hired for the yearly summer concert tour in Hampton Roads with the Tidewater Winds Concert Band

#### CS DEPARTMENT AMBASSADOR | JMU COMPUTER SCIENCE DEPARTMENT | DECEMBER 2019 - CURRENT

- Increased department outreach to prospective students
- Represent JMU CS at public events and online through social media
- Designed and taught workshops for local public-school students visiting JMU CS

## SOFTWARE ENGINEERING INTERN | NSCWDD DAM NECK | MAY 2019 - JULY 2019

- 10-week paid internship with the US Navy at Dam Neck Naval Base in Virginia Beach
- Secret Level security clearance
- Developed virtual reality training simulations for the Varjo XR-1 headset in Unity 3D using C#